it's fine you guys we got this everything was going well until the goal just stay calm okay
let's add our usual possession soccer with short passes i think we should try balancing it out
let's combine the short passes with what we've been working on i disagree didn't we say we were
going to go full direct this match we spent the whole week practicing this stuff for a reason
well our long balls aren't working for us anymore we're only 20 minutes into the damn game as soon
as we get a little pushback we refer to our same old style we need to get our priorities straight
yeah and who are you to say that tachibana's not wrong here man bailing looks pathetic what i agree
what's going on over there guys get back in position i don't need your amateur advice
got that tachibana you haven't done jack shit so you have no right to be telling us how to play
just ignore him we shouldn't back down i'm with you on that
i'm sure everyone who busted ass at the evening training sessions is too you're speaking for all
of us but it doesn't even matter we're still first years and as much as it sucks there's no one
experienced or trusted enough to lead our team yet he's an incredible playmaker
and as wait
oh
i
you
yeah
i
you
already
Let's go! Time for the restart!
Use the momentum to grab another goal, Musashino!
Huh? What's up with Asperion's formation?
They've got the two center backs way in the back for some reason, all by themselves,
and then pushed the full backs and holding midfielder way up into the half.
It's just like they practiced.
Yes. I think they made the right decision.
No backing down. Play direct and commit to it.
Now that they have more numbers in midfield,
their options for hitting and receiving long balls are greatly increased.
Tachibana!
I'll mark him! Don't worry! Tachibana's a decoy!
Huh?
There's a space out front.
All I need to do is hit the middle of the ball.
Come on!
Please score!
Somebody!
Doesn't matter who, as long as we score, right?
Wrong.
That's how this works. Right now, this is our best team.
I owe Coach Nozomi for showing faith in me.
Payback time.
It'll be me!
I'll be the one who scores!
Huh?
Counter attack!
Mushishino's interplay is perfect!
They can adjust their game in no time flat.
Espirion has next to no players in their own half!
Ugh!
That wasn't Defel!
What? He's already back there?
Man, Tachibana's ridiculously fast!
You know, Tachibana,
it can be a little dramatic at times. Just saying.
There's plenty of blame to go around, Tachibana,
so don't take it all on yourself.
Gotta ease up, man.
I need to show them what I can do.
I will!
Intercept!
The last thing we want to do is let that loser score!
Get in there!
They're coming up for a high double press!
Mushishino has enough players to repel him.
Breaking Fury will be very difficult.
Soichiro...
Pass it back this way!
I usually would.
I'd avoid losing possession.
Avoid all risks.
Yeah!
Tachibana!
That move was amazing.
Awesome!
I guess you're feeling better today.
Hit a long pass out to me!
I'll take it over here, then send it in the cross.
Get in the box, Tachibana.
I can help you score that goal!
Right.
I'm counting on you.
Oh no, you won't!
Crap!
Can I reach it?
Determination.
That's what's gotten us this far.
But is it enough?
Will it carry us to the end?
That's right.
Well, maybe.
Unlike those other grumpy forwards I met.
The strength you have lies in something completely different.
Watching those guys play forward,
with their insane skills and obsession with scoring,
really got me down.
But then I watched you.
You were different.
Who said anything about giving up?
You don't back down, Ashito.
I would gain strength and encouragement from seeing you fight.
You always face challenges head on.
Can you teach me how to be just like you?
That means the first player I ever really looked up to
was you, Ashito.
You did it so amazing!
Your first goal of the season!
And what a crazy goal!
You showed him what's up, that's for sure!
Huh.
The sleepy chump finally scored.
Well, good for him.
I scored.
That really happened!
What?
It really happened!
Huh.
You guys are so worthless.
I'm happy for you, Tachibana.
Tachibana, you deserve this.
You did that, man!
That was real life!
It wouldn't be so bad if anyone else in that team had scored the goal.
I'm feeling invincible.
Damn it!
We know better than anyone how strong a player Tachibana is.
And it looks like he's finally figured it out, too.
That was brilliant!
If he keeps this up, he'll be able to start up attacks.
And be the one to score in the end.
Steal it!
Damn it!
Okay.
I can sense it now.
Everyone on Musashino is afraid of me.
Maybe they always have been.
They're starting to make mistakes, guys!
Time to put the pressure on them!
Ultima!
The left wing!
I can use this.
They're scared.
And fear on the field is a double-edged sword.
Don't you dare let them shoot!
There's only one way to conquer those fears.
Only one place.
Right here on the field.
Once we've conquered our fears,
we plant new fears in the hearts of our opponents!
He's going back!
Thanks, Tachibana.
This is for you!
You gave me the courage!
I want to score now, too!
He's offside.
Oh, man.
You're wrong!
Still counts!
Not offside!
Cut it out, Ashito!
I made sure I stayed onside!
There's no way I was offside, you jerks!
Ashito!
Nice try there!
Let's focus on the next one!
Your obsession for scoring motivated me
and got me excited again.
I decided that I would make a final choice this game.
Do I want to be a forward or a defender?
Well, I made my decision, Tachibana.
And you were my inspiration.
Scoring lights me up.
It makes my heart race.
It lives inside me somehow!
That's what soccer is about to me!
And all I want to do!
Unbelievable.
He's Asperion's MVP now.
Tachibana, huh?
It seems he's revived Asperion all on his own.
Honestly, I don't know whether to laugh or cry.
He has certainly grown.
It's true.
But he's not the MVP I was talking about.
What?
It's number 33.
33?
Really?
So, you're looking at Ashito Aoi, then?
He's still a first-year.
Well, they fish in a pretty large pool.
That's Asperion.
He's made some impressive plays.
Two phenomenal long balls.
That's rare in one game.
His skills might not be the best, but he's been great about seeing where the players are.
By the time number 36 got half a touch on the ball, he was already off and running.
That's how he caught up.
And there's something else that proves just how wide his vision is.
Uh-huh.
His instructions.
It's going to be tight, but not impossible.
Should I force it home?
Leave it, Tachibana!
He utilizes his teammates, then comes in for the final blow.
It's incredible.
Good work, Tachibana.
Nice dummy pass there.
Ashito, let's slam this corner kick home.
Come on!
I need a minute to figure this out.
I have to get into a position where I can finish.
I can do this.
I can score as a fullback.
If I make forward runs, I'll be the one to score a goal.
Right now!
It's early to switch, but let's do it.
Let's do it.
Hey.
What are you doing all the way out here?
Seriously.
Don't you want to sit closer?
I don't know.
Oh, God!
Wait what the heck changing formation all outfield players have pushed up
That's an extremely high line with all ten of them out there like that. It's quite an unorthodox strategy
It might be an extreme move, but it's definitely increased the number of players who can join the high press
There's no need to panic I know exactly what Musashino's up to
Instead of huddling around their goal, they're being aggressive with the high press
Hmm, it's just numbers against numbers, right?
Whatever this is too much
There's no way they feel confident about this change especially with that huge unprotected space behind them
He got through all right
Offside that was totally offside
I'm sorry Tachibana. I messed up. I was a bit late with that lead pass. No worries, man
No worries, man
What again? No way!
It's an offside trap
We can aim for that space with our long balls
But it isn't doing any good
They're just gonna keep on putting us offside
On putting us offside
Focus guys we still have possession of the ball in midfield. We just got to find a way to solve this offside problem
Pass it to Tachibana
I can't believe I'm about to follow Aoi's instructions
Oh he's got it! He's going through! And the flag isn't up!
The right thing to do is keep attacking! I know it! I can see their fear! It's blastered all over their faces! Look at that ridiculously huge space behind them! There's no way they can pretend they aren't terrified! So we gotta keep attacking!
And I'm gonna score big this time!
Aoi's got it! Oh he's got it! He's going through! And the flag isn't up!
The right thing to do is keep attacking! I know it! I can see their fear! It's blastered all over their faces! Look at that ridiculously huge space behind them! There's no way they can pretend they aren't terrified! So we gotta keep attacking! And I'mma score big this time!
Great! That's it! Do it, Muto! There it is. That Esperion weakness. As predicted.
I wonder. Am I too tense today? The ball keeps bouncing off me. Gotta relax. Breathe it out. Remember that everything you've done has been for this moment.
What are you doing, Kaneda? Hustle! Kaneda, run!
Let us wait!
Our plan was to counterattack by going direct all the way. But this time, they countered us instead.
dead. It's fine. Don't worry. Just keep the momentum and we'll catch up in no time. Aim for that
space. Asuri, look out! No! You idiot! All the way! I know that one was my fault. We gotta find
some way to start their momentum! What is wrong with you guys? It worked. We used a high line
to sneak in a counterattack. I knew it was a gamble and that they were afraid of what
could happen. But they stuck it out and they took risks. This is Musashino's soccer. You
just proved it to them. And in the most effective way. That kind of blindside is humiliating.
Having their tactic thrown back in their faces makes the sting of giving up a goal even worse.
This could be a blow to Aspirion's morale. They'll be at even more of a loss than ever
after how that played out. And they've got no one to help them rally. All we have to do
hold on! This is going to be the last action of the half! As soon as we get it, just kick
it out!
Over here!
Damn.
I have something to ask you, Muto. A favor, really.
If you hit a long ball on the counter, or a pass in front of the goal, do you think you
could aim it between those two for me? I'd appreciate it.
The two over there?
Those center backs are a weak spot. Thing is, they don't work well as a pair.
How the hell? How'd I pull it off?
How did I crawl my way back? By scoring. That was the only way I could console myself
enough to go on. When I discovered skills that I lacked, I would practice every day like
my life depended on it. I was obsessed with goals. Obsessed!
Kuroda! Are you okay? Stretcher! We need a stretcher! Come on, man. Kuroda!
The scoring goals. That's all he cares about. It's an obsession!
And the first half ends with a brooist cheer, huh? Did we concede another goal? If we manage
to keep them out, we might be able to catch up.
Do you think so? But they were being pushed so hard.
What? There's only one person who can rally the team.
And I wonder how he plans to do it, considering he's only got 15 minutes for a quick pep talk.
What do you say we go watch?
Next time on Awashi, do your best, don't lose, fight to your limits.